







SKILLS

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

JavaScript,ReactJs,TypeScript,SCSS, REST API

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Accessibility,Ant Design, CSS,HTML,JavaScript, MaterialUI, ReactJS, Redux,SCSS,Styled Component,TypeScript

BACK-END DEVELOPMENT

NodeJs, Express

DATABASE MANAGEMENT

mongoDB,PostgreSQL

TESTING

Jest, Cypress

DEVOPS

Github Actions, bash scripting docker, Kubernetes

OTHER

Figma

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent

Finnish - Novice

CERTEFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF)
Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals

MESFIN TEGEGNE

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Espoo, Finland

Greetings! I'm a passionate FullIstack Developer with a love for crafting engaging user experiences. My journey in application development began quite some time ago, and along the way, I proudly earned a Bachelor's degree in Media Engineering. Applying my skills in various professional environments, I've honed my expertise in designing eye-catching User Interfaces, which I consider the heartbeat of my development work. Excitingly, I'm currently on a quest to master additional skills in Full-stack Development and Cloud Computing, transforming myself into a versatile contributor ready to tackle new challenges. Let's build something amazing together!

RECENT PROJECTS

Country API

JavaScript, ReactJs, Redux, Typescript, Material-Ul

Country API is web project where a list of countries are collected from an open API endpoint. The goal of the project is to provide a list of countries and their respective capital cities. countries can be added to a cart and also can be removed from the cart. The project is deployed on netlify.

Book Library

JavaScript, ReactJs,Redux, Typescript, Material-UI, NodeJs, ExpressJs, mongoDB Book Library is a MERN application, which I developed a RESTapi for the library. The API is consumed by the frontend which is displaying for users to borrow and return books.Only registered users can borrow books.The library also has a filtering features when books can be filted by authors name,or genre.

Note Taking App

JavaScript, ReactJs, Material-UI

Note-Taking-App is useful for our daily and routine task collection, A user can add notes or anything planned to accomplish daily.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Integrify | Helsinki, Finland | October 2021 - March 2022

- Sharpening competence as a full Stack Developer by collaborating with other developers of different seniorities an a diverse range of projects and real-life challenges.
- Focusing on front end development with JavaScript, typeScript, ReactJs, Redux in addition to othertechnologies and concepts such as accessibility and animations.
- Building back end for web based applications with frameworks such as NodeJs and ExpressJs.
- Covering additional concepts such as API development and decumentation, unit testing with Jest, SQI and NOSQL databases and version control with Github.
- Working with DeveOps practices (Bash scripting, Docker containers , and CI/CD with Github Actions and cloud Services with AWS.

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

CodingForAll | Espoo, Finland | June 2021 - August 2021

- Designed a prototype for a quize maker applications.
- Coverted the prototype to a functional applicatopn.
- Wrote reports and documentation.
- Technologies used: Figma, JavaScript, ReactJs

FRONT END DEVELOPER TRAINEE

Firma Informatyczna BigsonDev | Warsaw, Poland | November 2020 - January 2021

Supported the Lead Front-End Developer on various consulting and internal projects.

EDUCATION

B.ENG. IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Laurea University of Applied Sciences | Espoo, Finland | July 2016 - Present

B.ENG, IN MEDIA ENGINEERING, APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

Metropolia University of Applied Sciences | Espoo, Finland | July 2007 - May 2011